



Tomislav Pilipac

Date of birth: 07/06/1989 | **Nationality:** Croatian | **Phone number:** (+385) 917540961 (Mobile)

Email address: tpilipac@gmail.com

Address: Cesta Šibenik - Perković 77, 22000, Šibenik, Croatia (Home)

ABOUT ME

Resourceful and dedicated bachelor's degree historian and croatologist with 5 years experience in working with archival records and documentation. Highly organized, and skilled in written and verbal communication, proficient at programming, computer technology and experienced in using IT equipment. Committed to pursuit new skills and improvement on every level both individually and through dedicated team work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

05/10/2016 - 01/07/2017 Zagreb, Croatia

ARCHIVIST CROATIAN MEMORIAL-DOCUMENTATION CENTER OF THE HOMELAND WAR

Digital processing, classification and preservation of audio and video materials from Croatian War of Independence. Acquired knowledge of computer skills and working with different types of IT equipment.

01/04/2018 - 31/08/2023 Zagreb, Croatia

PROJECT TEAM MEMBER MINISTRY OF CROATIAN VETERANS

Digital processing, classification and preservation of highly classified archival records from Croatian War of Independence. I managed large volumes of archival records, ensuring their digital preservation and classification. These roles required precision, attention to detail, and the ability to work with structured and unstructured data—skills that directly translate to database management. With unstructured data, I had to be especially precise to ensure accurate categorization and integration into searchable systems. Acquired knowledge of computer skills and working with different types of IT equipment. Effectively multitasked and worked well with internal and external teams.

10/07/2024 - 30/09/2024 Šibenik, Croatia

WORKHOUSE OPERATOR ROTO DINAMIC

Execution of the accurate handling, packing and storage of materials in a warehouse. Receiving goods, label them, check quality, store the goods and document any damage. Monitoring stock levels of items, keep inventory and ship goods.

18/10/2024 - CURRENT Drniš, Croatia

MIXER OPERATOR ALUFLEXPACK

Operate manufacturing equipment within Company specifications and procedures. Manufacture Company products within the specifications given and follow Company procedures, as assigned by the Production Supervisor or Team Lead. Prepare and setup correct quantities of raw materials for production lines. Prepare product samples for Quality Control Department according to Company policies and procedures, for in-process and final product testing. Transfer finished products to correct storage and shipping containers and label according to Company policies and procedures.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/10/2011 - 01/10/2014 Zagreb, Croatia

BACHELOR OF HISTORY AND CROATOLOGY University of Zagreb, Faculty of Croatian Studies

Address Borongajska cesta 83d, 10000, Zagreb, Croatia | Website https://www.hrstud.unizg.hr/en

TRAINEE AT TROKUT NEET ACADEMY Trokut Šibenik

Address Ul. Velimira Škorpika 7/a, 22000, Šibenik, Croatia, Šibenik, Croatia | Website https://tomislavpilip.github.io/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): CROATIAN

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C1	C1	B2	B2	B2
ITALIAN	A2	A2	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

JavaScript | Postgres SQL | Knowledge of SQL. | TypeScript | React | Microsoft Excel | Good listener and communicator | Decision-making | Microsoft Office | Adobe (Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe Indesign, Adobe Premiere) | Organizational and planning skills | Team-work oriented | Motivated | Responsibility